吃晚餐啦
Dinner!
我超愛國際菜卷餅之夜
I love international taco night.
我們有...
We have...
法國薯條  希臘奶酪
French fries, Greek Yogurt,
加拿大培根  中國面條
Canadian bacon, Chinese noodles,
意大利香腸  美國干酪
Italian sausage, American cheese,
以及智利的特產  紅辣椒
and from the country of Chile, chili.
其實就是把冰箱中那些快要變質的食物
Kind of just seems like we're eating all the food
一起弄出來搞個大雜燴吧
in the fridge that was about to go bad.
是的  但是是用卷餅包著的哦
Yes, but in a taco shell.
有點像是在聯合國吃自助餐
This is like the buffet at the United Nations
只不過沒有混蛋警察
without all the grab-ass.
喜旺  瞧  這些面條都是中國進口
Hope, look, these noodles were made all the way in China
是些跟你年紀一樣大的小姑娘做的
by little girls the same age as you.
其實  在中國
You know, in China
他們吃的面條和我們這的
they actually eat a completely different
完全不一樣
kind of noodle than we have here.
我不想讓人覺得我搞種族歧視
I don't want to sound racist,
但我真覺得所有中國面條都是一個樣
but I kind of think all Chinese noodles look alike.
好吧  我只是說說
Yeah. I'm just saying.
我小時候我們家經常出去旅行
My family used to travel a lot when I was a kid.
中國  阿根廷  澳大利亞
China, Argentina, Australia...
我小時候就知道什么時候該閉嘴
When I was a kid, I learned to keep my mouth shut
別喋喋不休  好像自己無所不知似的
and not be such an annoying know-it-all.
我小時候其實也經常出去旅行呢
You know, we went on a lot of trips when I was little, too.
吃完晚飯給你看出游照片
I should, uh, show you the vacation photos after dinner.
爛主意
Uh, that's a terrible idea.
沒人喜歡看別人家的出游照片
Nobody likes to look at other people's vacation photos.
再說  那些照片也早就不在了
Besides, those pictures don't exist anymore.
是啊
Yeah.
它們都熔化在了...
They melted in a...
那場奇怪的只在架子上燃燒的大火中
strangely contained shelf fire?
你們確定嗎
Are you sure?
我好像幾天前還看過呢
I thought I saw them a couple days ago.
這些卷餅到底該是硬的還是軟的啊
Are these supposed to be hard or soft shell tacos?
那是餐巾紙  曾奶奶
That's a napkin, Maw Maw.
那些墨西哥人還會創造出什么美食呢
What will those Mexicans think of next?
那是我們去湖泊世界時拍的
And that is when we went to Lake World.
天啊  鯰魚秀真是太精彩了
Oh, man, the catfish show was amazing.
瞧瞧你  一副蔫搭搭的樣子
Look at you, all tuckered out.
這是我們去佛蒙特滑雪的時候拍的
Oh, and this is when we went skiing in Vermont.
我們住的大木屋就在本和杰瑞旁邊
We stayed in this big cabin next to Ben and Jerry.
不  不是生產冰激凌的那兩位
No, not the ice cream guys,
只是一對度假的同志夫夫
just a gay couple on vacation.
你又是昏睡狀態的
You're asleep again.
是啊  我一出去度假就暈車
Yeah, I always used to get carsick on vacations
所以我爸媽就會讓我吃藥
so my parents would give me medicine
讓我昏沉沉的
and it would make me kind of drowsy.
我們要么看他吐  要么讓他睡
We had to choose between a puker and a sleeper.
最終我們選擇讓他睡
We chose sleeper.
嘿  我不是想轉移話題
Hey, not to change the subject,
不過  只有我一個人這么覺得嗎
but is it just me,
好像最近什么東西上都時興加尼龍搭扣了
or is there a lot more Velcro on stuff lately?
天空中那塊棕黃色的印跡是什么
Yeah, what is this brown stain in the sky?
-是風暴云吧  -我的胃中一陣翻滾難受
- Storm cloud. - I'm starting to get a weird feeling in my stomach.
在山的這邊竟然還有道裂縫
There's a rip in the side of this mountain.
當然會有了
Of course there is.
那是裂縫山
That's Rip Mountain.
天啊
Oh, my God.
這些都是假的
These are all fake.
好吧  有些確實是假的
Fine. Some of them are fake.
但第一張是真的
But the first one's real.
你小的時候  其他孩子都炫耀說
When you were little, all the other kids
去湖泊世界玩什么的
were bragging about going to Lake World,
所以我們就帶你去了
so we took you.
但你暈車了  所以我們就喂你吃了暈車藥
But you got carsick, so we gave you medicine.
那不僅讓你在駕車過程中是昏睡的
Not only did it knock you out for the drive,
你那一整天都睡過去了
you slept through the whole day.
第二天早上
And the next morning,
你就不停地說
all you could talk about
你在湖泊世界玩得有多開心
was what a great time you had at Lake World.
我們就心想  何必止步于此呢
So we figured, why stop there?
不如讓你擁有遍游全國的美好記憶吧
Why not give you great memories of seeing the whole country?
快喝  寶貝
Drink up, honey.
開車去夏威夷很遠呢
It's a long drive to Hawaii.
一旦你進入夢鄉
Once you were in dreamland,
我們就開車穿越小鎮
we'd just drive across town
去到攝影室后面的垃圾站
to the dumpster behind the photography studio.
我在附近偷瞄著他們
I did landscaping nearby,
所以每次我看到他們扔掉布景
so every time I saw them throw out a backdrop,
我們就知道度假時間來了
we knew it was vacation time.
我們遍游各地
We went everywhere.
我們給了吉米一個孩子能擁有的
We gave Jimmy the greatest
最完美的假想式童年回憶
imaginary childhood a kid could have.
就是說
So you're telling me
我沒用過那個貓王死在上面的馬桶  是嗎
I never used the toilet that Elvis died on?
我現在還在到處吹噓這事呢
I mean, I still brag about that!
沒關系的  吉米  沒關系的
Shh. It's okay, Jimmy. It's okay.
反正到最后都會變成布魯克林橋下的河水
It's all water under the Brooklyn Bridge.
現在我們知道你其實從沒見過那橋
Which we now know you never actually saw.
重要的是
The important thing is that
我們要努力為喜旺創造更美好的回憶
we're gonna work harder for Hope.
我們當年可是努力得很呢
We worked pretty hard.
我只是說我們要帶她去真正旅行而已
I just mean we're gonna take her on a real vacation.
哇塞  真正的旅行啊
Oh. A "Real" Vacation.
兩個雜貨店打工的  祝你們好運啊
Good luck with that on two grocery baggers' salaries.
其實不必非要奢華啊
It doesn't have to be fancy
只要我們一家人清醒地
as long as we're together.
在一起就好
And awake.
根本不值得那樣做
It's not worth it.
家庭旅行只會讓每一個人都失控
Family vacations just get everybody out of sync.
她說得對
She's right.
其實就是整天開車  被太陽曬傷
It's nothing but driving and sunburns
還有不斷爭吵
and a whole lot of fighting.
你怎么知道  你從沒帶我們去過任何地方
How would you know? You never took us anywhere.
瞧吧  我們已經在吵了
See? We're already fighting.
很快我們就會被太陽曬傷
Pretty soon we're gonna be sunburned.
我們可能是沒有帶吉米真正旅行過
Maybe we didn't give Jimmy real vacations.
但我們給了他真實的回憶
But we gave him real memories.
反正小孩子出去旅行的收獲也就是回憶罷了
And that's all kids remember from vacations anyway... is memories.
現在吉米的回憶都被毀了
And now all Jimmy's memories are ruined.
謝謝你  海倫·凱勒[盲人作家]
Thank you, Helen Keller.
我覺得你想說的應該不是這個人吧
I don't think that's who you think it is.
就那個女警探
Yeah, the girl detective.
你想的是阿米莉亞·艾哈特[女權運動者]
You're thinking of Amelia Earhart.
南茜·德魯  你想說的是神探南茜
Nancy Drew. You're thinking of Nancy Drew.
我完全不記得有這號人物
Doesn't ring a bell.
那不重要
It's not important.
事實是  吉米之前很開心
The fact is, Jimmy was happy,
很無知  以為自己遍游各地
well-traveled and ignorant,
因為你  他現在知道了真相了
and you just took away two of those things.
我真不愿意承認你媽是對的
I hate to think your mother is right,
但這里的所有旅行路線都要好幾千美元
but all the vacations in here cost thousands of dollars.
你查看美洲獅油輪路線了嗎
Have you looked into a cougar cruise?
美洲獅也指如狼似虎的饑渴中年婦女
加勒比海灘三夜之旅
It's three nights on the Caribbean.
非常狂野哦
It's pretty wild.
弗蘭克  我們在計劃家庭旅行
Frank, we're trying to plan a family vacation,
而不是和老女人亂搞
not have sex with older women.
不  是真正的美洲獅哦
No, these are actual live cougars.
你和它們一起飄洋過海
You sail the high seas with them.
差不多就是根據那部搞笑片《少年派》設計的
It's loosely based off that hilarious movie Life of Pi.
但這是游艇游
But it is a cruise,
所以  如果你愛熟女的話
so... there are a lot of older women,
那里有很多哦
if you're into that.
看看這個
Check this out.
我是說  雖然這不是美洲獅游艇游
I mean, it's no cougar cruise,
但這至少還算是乘船游了
but at least it's still a boat trip.
邊度假邊掙錢
"Travel and make money."
聽起來很棒啊
Oh, that sounds cool.
你知道還有什么事很棒嗎
You know what else is cool?
別在你們沒邀請的人面前談論
Not talking about the awesome trips you're gonna take
你們即將開始的美妙旅程
in front of someone you haven't invited.
你們還有機會噢
Yet.
猜猜怎么著
Guess what.
你們錯了
You guys were wrong.
塞布麗娜給我們找到一個很棒的度假計劃
Sabrina found us a great vacation.
你沒看到我們在給曾奶奶洗牙嗎
Can't you see we're doing a teeth cleaning?
如果你把她弄醒了
If you startle Maw Maw awake,
我跟你媽中有個人得掉根指頭
one of us could lose a finger.
嘿  你看
Hey, look.
這是大富翁游戲的那個小鐵片
It's the little iron from the Monopoly set.
我們有一年多沒玩了
We haven't played in over a year.
我們得更經常給她洗洗牙
We should really floss her more often.
我們是來邀請你們
We came over here to invite you guys
來一次真正的家庭度假
on a real family vacation.
不是在小巷外或者是
One that will take place outside of an alley
垃圾車邊上
and nowhere near a Dumpster.
我得看下我的行程表
Let me check my calendar.
沒空不去
Pass.
你們玩得開心
You guys have fun.
這兒就是我們的天堂
We got our paradise right here.
看  這是個棋盤游戲的幸運符
Look, it's a game board bonanza.
我估計是馬斯塔德上校的燭臺
Think I found Colonel Mustard's candlestick.
馬斯塔德上校  推理棋牌游戲Cluedo的角色
不  只是個牙齒填充物罷了
No. That's just a filling.
你們倆真的不跟
You guys sure you don't want to go
我們去度假嗎
on this vacation with us?
聽著  這個富裕的瓦德克拉姆家庭
Look, this rich Vanderklam family
花500美金請我們幫忙把船順流而下
is paying us 500 bucks to go sail their boat
開到富爾頓碼頭
down the river to the Fulton Marina.
然后我們就能用
Then we're gonna use
用那筆錢在那住兩晚
that money on two nights at a hotel
并乘火車回納什維爾
and train tickets back to Natesville.
你知道我在想什么嗎
You thinking what I'm thinking?
游艇性愛
Boat sex?
什么
Excuse me?
你剛剛是說"游艇性愛"嗎
Did you just say "Boat sex"?
我們有一張"交通工具性愛"待辦表
We've got this whole "Transportation sex" Checklist
我們正在努力實現中
we're plowing through.
對了  犁
Ooh, a plow!
這玩意有在表上嗎
Is that even on the list?
剛剛加上了
It is now.
這從數年前
This all started years ago
我跟你媽藏在行李艙里蹭車時就開始了
when your mom and I snuck a ride on a bus.
我們應該等到比較顛簸的路段再辦事
We should wait for a bumpy section of highway
那樣咱倆不用動就能爽了
and let the road do all the work.
你太聰明了
You're so smart.
謝了  戴爾
Thanks, Dale.
嗯  那個
Well, uh...
我希望你們一起去
I was hoping that you'd want to come with
這樣就是我們全家共同的回憶了
to be part of our family memories.
當然  我們去
Oh, definitely. We're in.
我們要坐前排
We are gonna have front-row seats
來迎接這場度假災難
for this vacation disaster.
好  就這樣了
Okay, that's it.
把腌黃瓜拿來
Get the pickle.
曾爺爺以前就是這樣弄醒我的
That's how Paw Paw used to wake me up.
當然
Of course,
他那根比這小點  味道還不好聞
his pickle was smaller and smelled a lot worse.
你好  我們是來這把瓦德克拉姆家的船開到
Uh, we're here to take the Vanderklams' boat
富爾頓碼頭的
to the Fulton Marina.
我喜歡你們的穿著
I like how you dressed the part.
很少人開車拖船時
It's not often you see folks get so decked out
會如此盛裝打扮
just to tow a boat down the highway.
我們是要拖過去
We're towing it?
你在搞笑嗎
We... Are you kidding me?
我還以為要把游艇開過去
I thought we were gonna take it out on the water.
我還以為吉米·巴菲特[歌手]是個好榜樣呢
And I thought Jimmy Buffett was a good role model.
玩得開心點
Have a great trip.
搞毛啊
Aw, man.
看來暈車藥派上用場了
Bet carsick medicine sounds real good now.
你們倆只要給個訊號
You two just give the signal
這玩意還是99%純果汁呢
and it's nighty-night juice all around.
你看宣傳單上  這船明顯不在拖車上的嘛
Now, on the flyer, the boat is clearly not on a trailer.
這太容易誤解了
It's highly misleading.
嗯  我們帶吉米度假時
Well, nothing like this ever happened
從沒發生過這種事
when we took Jimmy on vacations.
沒事發生  是因為一直昏迷壓根就不是度假
Nothing happened because being unconscious is not a vacation.
我不敢茍同
I beg to differ.
這樣吧  沿途好像有家
Now, it looks like there's
填充毛絨玩具博物館
a Stuffed Animal Museum right on the way,
那里應該會給喜旺美好的回憶
and that'd be a great memory for Hope.
我跟伯特要在游艇里面
Burt and I will ride on the boat.
讓你們倆有點私人空間
Just to give you two some privacy.
我去后備箱
I'll grab the champagne and the boombox
拿香檳跟音響
out of the back of the car,
我們啟航吧
we'll set sail.
喂  喂  喂
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
別想太多
No, no.
誰也不能進船
No one is allowed in the boat.
你看過合同沒啊
Didn't you read the contract?
當然 每個字都看了
Oh, yeah, I read every word.
結果我女兒穿的像蛙人一樣  去公路旅行
That's why my daughter's wearing a snorkel on a road trip.
還有我不知道的事嗎
Is there anything else I might've missed?
如果你下午4點前送不到那碼頭的話
If you don't get the boat there by 4:00 P.M.,
你只能拿一半錢
you forfeit half the money.
哦
Right.
這么說我們得在
So that means we had to leave, what?
30分鐘前出發
30 minutes ago?
大家趕緊上車
Everyone get in the car.
趕緊的
Go, go, go, go, go!
對不起對不起對不起
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
抱歉
Sorry.
可以停車嗎  塞布麗娜
Can we please stop the car, Sabrina?
我們已經憋了五個小時了
We've been holding it for five hours.
原來我們得憋著啊
We're supposed to be holding it?
今天才知道
That's news to me.
我也是
Me, too.
我們下個加油站停車
We're gonna stop at the next gas station.
之前的五個加油站你也是這么說的
That's what you said about the last five gas stations.
下個加油站比較大
The next gas station that has room
船進得去出得來
for a boat to go in and out of it.
再堅持會
Just hang in there.
看著好像還有一英里就到了
It looks like there's one coming up in about a mile.
填充毛絨玩具博物館也還有
Hey, the Stuffed Animal Museum's
一英里就要到了
coming up in about a mile.
我們順便去一下
We're gonna be stopped right by it.
吉米  咱現在得先把船送到
Okay, Jimmy, delivering the boat is our priority right now.
只是想提醒你  別忘了那博物館
Just wanted to make sure you didn't forget about the museum.
你這么一直念叨我還真忘不掉
It's hard to forget about it when you mention it ten times.
聽起來有人像是要失控了
Sounds like somebody's getting a little out of sync.
我們沒失控
We're not out of sync!
別再說"水槽"了[諧音失控]
Please don't say "Sink."
或者是其他我以前尿過的東西
Or the name of anything else I have ever peed in.
趕緊去  我們只有十分鐘
Go quickly. We only have ten minutes.
加油站兼食品店
五分鐘后
好了
Okay.
快
Come on.
搞毛
What...?
車去哪了
Where the hell is the car?
偷偷說一句
Hey, between you and me?
咱的假期開始有意思了
This vacation's starting to get interesting.
搞毛
Wha...?
這不科學
What?This doesn't make any sense.
怎么會有人放著游艇不要去偷車
Why would somebody take the car but leave the boat?
因為沒有人想拖游艇
Because nobody wants to tow a boat?
以前我們去裂縫山時  從沒發生過這種事
Nothing like this ever happened to us at Rip Mountain.
這是個災難征兆
It's a sign.
先把每種動物都收集雌雄兩只
First we gather two of every kind of animal.
接著我們等著就好[暗示諾亞方舟典故]
Then we wait.
動物標本博物館
stuffed animial又有填充毛絨玩具的意思
沒事  我能搞定
Okay, I got this.
吉米  你帶喜旺和曾奶奶
Jimmy, I just want you to take Hope and Maw Maw
去毛絨玩具博物館
and go into the Stuffed Animal Museum, okay?
我去報警
I'm gonna call the cops.
大家別著急
Don't worry, everybody.
時間還很充裕
There's still plenty of time
夠咱們制造美好的家庭回憶
to make some happy family memories, okay?
咱的車才被偷了
Our car was just stolen.
我不想讓你一個人處理這堆爛事
I don't want to leave you on your own to deal with this.
吉米  我們是來找樂子的
Jimmy... we came here to have fun,
我們一定會很歡樂的  靠
and we are gonna have fun, damn it.
趕緊帶上孩子
So take the kid
還有這瘋老婆子
and take the crazy old lady,
給我進去
and go in there
制造一些美好的回憶
and make some happy memories!
能做到嗎
Okay?
能
All right.
咱們制造回憶去
Let's go make some memories!
制造回憶去咯
Let's make some memories.
看著游艇
Watch the boat.
你要干嘛
What are you doing?
我絕不會讓偷車的小毛賊破壞我的假期
No punk car thief is gonna take down my vacation.
如果我五分鐘內沒回來  就去地獄找我吧
If I'm not back in five minutes, forward my mail to Hell.
開玩笑啦
I'm just kidding.
如果我五分鐘內沒回來  一定記得叫救護車啊
If I'm not back in five minutes, please call an ambulance.
我盡力了
Tried to warn her.
就跟她說度假煩事多嘛
Vacations are a disaster.
現在游艇是咱倆的了
Hey, we have that boat all to ourselves.
她叫咱倆看著游艇
She said watch the boat.
又沒叫咱站在外面看著
Didn't say watch it from outside.
來吧
Come on... whoa!
這對吉米的嬰兒床管用  游艇也應該沒問題
Good enough for Jimmy's crib, good enough for a boat.
歡迎來到動物標本博物館
Welcome to the Stuffed Animal Museum.
暢享奇觀  老少咸宜
A menagerie of wonders and merriment for all ages.
成人票  兒童票  老人票各一張
All right, well, one adult, one child and one senior, please.
老年人免票
seniors are free.
必須的嘛
Of course.
因為咱已經不是真正的人了
'Cause we're not real people anymore,
這衣服和皮膚都是靠屁撐著
just clothes and skin holding in farts.
你真是個開心果
Aren't you delightful!
你看起來絕對不超過85歲
You don't look a day over 85.
你也是喲
Likewise.
等你參觀完出來
Once you've gone through the tour,
我們不如
why don't we just, uh,
把假牙摘了  看看會發生什么
take our teeth out and see what happens.
實在不忍心打斷你們令人作嘔的對話
Not to interrupt this disgusting interaction,
但我四歲的閨女
but my four-year-old is real anxious
焦急地等著看毛絨玩具呢
to go see the stuffed animals.
你的意思應該是激動吧
I believe you mean to say "Excited."
焦急的意思是很焦慮
"Anxious" Means "Filled with anxiety."
現在這些年輕人都不講究語法啊
These kids today and their grammar.
進去以后
Okay, once inside,
跟著地上黃色的爪印走就行
just follow the yellow paw prints on the floor to guide you through.
好好享受哦
Enjoy.
明白
All right.
旅程即將開啟
We're gonna go through...
準備好了嗎  喜旺
You ready, Hope?
絕對是美妙的神奇之旅
This is gonna be awesome.
這不是我們說的那種可愛毛絨玩具啊
Not the cute kind of stuffed animals!
不可愛
Not cute!
轉不動
It won't spin this way.
救命啊
Help!
我們搞錯了
There's been some kind of misunderstanding.
放我們出去
Would you let us out!
跟著黃色爪印走
Please follow the yellow paw prints.
謝謝配合  好好享受
Thank you and enjoy.
曾奶奶  快幫我帶喜旺出去
Maw Maw, help me get Hope out of here.
我在跟這貓頭鷹比賽對視呢
Shh! I'm in a staring contest with this owl.
我本想運個游艇  度個開心的假期
I came here to deliver a boat and have a nice vacation.
現在我的假期全給毀了
And right now, I'm all out of vacation.
姐你在說什么
What does that even mean?
別怕  喜旺
It's okay, Hope.
我們只是在玩躲貓貓的恐怖加長版
We're just playing a long, creepy game of peek-a-boo.
我要去網上
I am gonna write a very negative
給你們博物館差評
online review of your museum!
去吧  我會刪掉的
Go ahead, I'll delete it.
你刪掉了我還會繼續寫
Well, then I'll write another one!
那我就繼續刪
Then I'll delete that one, too.
你行  那我不寫了
Fine! Then I'll probably give up at that point.
但我還是很生氣
But I'll still be very upset!
吉米
Jimmy!
去找那家伙要名片
Get this guy's card.
他真能干
He's good.
我之前在考慮火化
I was thinking cremation,
可是看到他把這老蝙蝠保養得這么好
but if he can make this old bat look good,
我想把我交給他應該也錯不了
imagine what he could do for me.
伯特  怎么了
Burt, what's going on?
可能有點問題
I think I'm having a little problem.
要來點我們在野外浴缸里激戰時
Do we have to get those pills
用的那種藥嗎
where we sit in bathtubs in a field?
不是  這家人的度假照片
No, I think I'm just distracted
讓我分心了
by these pictures of this family on vacation.
我在想我們以前是不是能讓吉米的童年更加美好
I'm wondering if we could've done better for Jimmy.
伯特  他們這些有游艇的土豪
Burt, these people are "Boat rich."
當然有資本享受豪華的假期了
Of course they had fancy vacations.
也不都是豪華的
But they're not all fancy vacations.
他們去遠足  去海邊
They went hiking, they went to the beach.
去納什維爾湖釣魚
They went fishing at Natesville Lake.
這湖離咱家很近
That's closer to our house than the Dumpster
比照相館后面的垃圾箱近多了
behind the photo studio.
接下來你就該同意塞布麗娜的想法了
Next you're gonna say you think Sabrina was right.
不會不會
No, no, no, no.
絕對不會
No!
肯定不會
No.
也許吧
Maybe.
也許
Maybe?
不是肯定也許
Not a definite maybe.
是可能大概也許
A maybe-ish maybe.
那
So...
就是說我不對咯
you're saying I'm wrong?
也許吧
Maybe?
你也許就是這個意思
Maybe you're saying that,
還是我也許錯了
or maybe I'm wrong?
或者
Or...
也許你是我見過的最美的女人
maybe you're the most beautiful woman I have ever seen.
也許你就自個兒在游艇上擼吧
Maybe you should have boat sex by yourself.
不要啊  維吉妮亞  這種事我已經在游艇上干過了
No, Virginia, I've already done that on a boat.
別介啊  維吉妮亞
Come on! Virginia!
維吉妮亞  別走
Virginia, wait!
我把車找回來了
I got the car back.
你倆...
You guys...
干啥呢
what are you doing?
瞧瞧  大英雄回來了
Look who saved the day
騎著偷來的摩托去追盜車賊
chasing thieves on her stolen motorcycle.
我們的萬事神通小姐
Little Miss Right About Everything.
我從沒說過她是萬事神通
I never said she was right about everything.
老天爺  她都蠢到嫁給吉米了
For God's sake, she married Jimmy.
這絕對是史上最糟的一次度假了
This is officially the worst vacation ever.
什么
Excuse me?
我為給這個家帶來一場前所未有的體驗
I have done absolutely everything I can do
已經使盡渾身解數了
to give this family something that they've never had before.
偷摩托車嗎
A stolen motorcycle?
不  一次真正的度假
No. A vacation.
你偷了一輛摩托
You stole a motorcycle?
是為了把車找回來
To get the car back.
吉米  我這是一種無私的英雄主義
Jimmy, it was a selfless act of heroism
不過是為了讓你們能盡情參觀泰迪熊博物館
so you could enjoy your time at the teddy bear museum.
那根本不是泰迪熊
They were not teddy bears.
它們是被填充的動物
They were stuffed animals.
是真正的動物
Real animals.
還是捕食中的動物
Eating other animals.
這會給喜旺留下一輩子的心理陰影的
Hope's going to be scarred for life.
幸好我偷拿了這只羚羊  也不算一無所獲
I pilfered this antelope, so the day wasn't a total loss.
你說得沒錯  伯特  我們做得不好
You're right, Burt, we messed up.
我們應該在吉米小時候  多帶他出去度假
When Jimmy was a kid, we should have taken him on vacation,
偷上一輛摩托  帶他去個恐怖博物館
stolen a motorcycle and gone to the museum of nightmares.
這種童年回憶肯定比我們假造的那些
Those would've been way better vacation memories
要美好多了
than we ever gave him.
這和我們給吉米的無關
It's not about what we gave Jimmy.
我們當年也算盡力了
We did the best we could with what we had.
我不后悔
I can live with that.
但如果我們支持他們  而不是挖苦  對著干
But they could do better with Hope if we're on their side,
喜旺就會得到更棒的體驗
not rooting against them.
摩托車之旅肯定很有趣吧
...A motorcycle ride would've been fun.
聽著  伙計們
You know what, you guys?
咱們還是趕緊把船拉上  送到地方
Let's just hitch up the boat and drop it off,
然后就能收工回家
then we can all just go home.
吉米  我懷疑你是基佬
Hey, Jimmy, I always suspected you fancied boys,
但你啥時候開始大張旗鼓地出柜了
but when did you start advertising it?
什么意思
What are you talking about?
你的保險桿貼紙上寫著"哥就是喜歡后庭"
Your bumper sticker says, "I'd rather be spelunking."
本意為山洞探險
這不是我們的車
This is not our car.
你們誰襲擊了這位先生  還偷走了他的車
Which one of you assaulted this man and stole his vehicle?
什么
What?
給老娘抱著
Hold this for me.
一個人坐牢就夠了
No reason both of us have to go to jail.
聽著  這太容易搞混了
Look, honestly, it's-it's such an easy mistake.
我們的車顏色一模一樣
Our-our cars are the exact same color...
她攻擊了我
She assaulted me!
我的蛋蛋現在還腫著呢
Do you know how swollen my testicles are?
你不給我們看  我們怎么知道
We'll never know unless you show us.
那個經營標本動物博物館的變態
That psycho from the Stuffed Animal Museum
才該被抓起來
is the real criminal!
這幾個瘋子根本沒沿著黃色熊掌印走
Those deviants didn't even follow the yellow paw prints!
他們直接從防火出口跑了
They went right out the fire exit!
給我把他們拷上  我要把他們做成標本
You cuff 'em, I'll stuff 'em!
都給我安靜點
Everybody quiet down.
請把手放到背后  小姐
Put your hands behind your back, miss.
你要逮捕我嗎
You're arresting me?
我唯一犯下的罪行就是愛心太泛濫
Look, my only crime is caring too much.
我是打了人  偷了車
I mean, sure, assault and grand theft auto,
但我的動機純粹是出于愛啊
but mostly just caring too much.
我只是想給女兒
Look, I just really wanted to give my daughter
創造一段美好的假期回憶
a fun vacation memory.
你要是逮捕她
If you're gonna arrest her,
就把我一起抓走吧
you're gonna have to arrest me, too.
-為什么  -因為要不是因為我
- Why? - She wouldn't have had to do any of this
沒有盡職盡責
if I just tried harder
帶我孫女度一場真正的假  她也不會這樣
to give my granddaughter a real vacation.
那個小可愛就是你的孫女嗎
Well, if that little cutie is your granddaughter,
別錯過這一幕了
you're missing it.
奶奶
Hey, Gram!
我在開船呢
I'm driving a boat.
喜旺
Hope!
請你等一下再逮捕我
Please, can you just wait one second to arrest me?
我真的好想把這段拍下來
I just... I really want to get this on video.
好的  等等
Okay. Stay there.
好了  喜旺  我們來創造美好回...
Come on, Hope, let's make a memor...
這下好了
Oh, yeah.
吉米嬰兒床的悲劇重演了
Same thing happened with Jimmy's crib.
我是在牢里嗎
Oh. Am I in jail?
不
No.
你撞到了頭  在醫院里呢
You hit your head; you're in the hospital.
好消息是
Good news is,
他們看見你像脫水的魚一樣
when they saw you flopping around
疼得在地上打滾
on the ground like a fish out of water,
就不忍心指控你了
they felt too bad to press charges.
太好了
Oh, that's good news.
但話說回來
Oh, on the flip side,
我帶喜旺過了一個糟糕透頂的假期
I just gave Hope the worst vacation ever.
我可不覺得喜旺會這么想
I don't think she feels that way.
看這個
Look at this.
你在我昏迷不醒的時候  把我弄上了船
You put me up on the boat while I was unconscious?
假期是你一手策劃的
Hey, I mean, you planned the whole thing.
我們怎么能不把你拍進去呢
We weren't gonna leave you out of the videos.
救護車來之前
And holding you upright,
我們一直讓你保持直立狀態
kept you from swallowing your tongue
免得你把舌頭吞下去了
till the ambulance got there.
看看這個
Check these out.
抓到貓嘍
Catfish!
抓到了
Whoa! Catch it!
很棒  是不是
Eh? That's good, right?
喜旺玩這么開心  我太高興了
Oh, I'm glad Hope had a good time.
維吉妮亞  你是對的
Virginia, you were so right.
真正的度假太麻煩了  得不償失
Having a real vacation is more trouble than it's worth.
這一趟是很糟
Well, this trip was awful.
哪里是度假啊  簡直是亡命之旅啊
This was more of a crime spree than a trip.
但明年  只要我們齊心協力
But next year, we could do better
就可以做得更好
if we all work together.
誰知道呢  也許有一天吉斯一家的旅行照里
And who knows, maybe someday the Chances will take a vacation
每個人都能是清醒的
where one of us isn't passed out in every picture.
那可就太好了
I would really like that.
但別再搞什么游艇了
But no more boats.
吉米  我怎么被曬傷了
Jimmy, how did I get so sunburned?
可能是我忘了給你擦防曬霜
I may have forgotten to put your sunscreen on.
我為你驕傲
Hey... I'm proud of you.
我知道  你愿意承認錯誤一定不容易
I know how hard it is for you to admit you're wrong.
不會啊
No, it isn't.
完全同意
I totally agree.
可惜現在沒有游艇了
Too bad there's no boat here.
沒關系
Oh, that's okay.
天涯何處無交通工具呢
Plenty of other vehicles in the sea.
快走  一個洞穴探險者的蛋蛋碎了
Let's go! We have a spelunker with a ruptured testicle!
和大活人跳舞的感覺
It's so nice to dance with something
真是好
that still has a pulse.
晚餐很可口
Dinner was lovely.
雞肉真鮮美
The chicken was delicious!
因為那不是雞肉
That's because it wasn't chicken.
是狐?肉[暗示《少年派》中吃狐?的情節]
It was meerkat.
家有喜旺
第四季 第三集
翻譯：澤生 迷藏 寧馨兒 爵士年代蓬蓬裙
校對：迷藏 寧馨兒    時間軸：加森
后期：隨風飛翔      總監：迷藏
■